Chapter 117.
The whale watch The four whales slain that evening had died wide apart, one far to windward,
one less distant to lure, one ahead, one a stern. These last three were brought
alongside air nightfall. But the windward one could not be reached till
morning, and the boat that had killed it lay by its side all night. and that boat
was Ahab's. The waifole was thrust upright into the dead whale's spout
hole, and the lantern hanging from its top cast a troubled, flickering glare
upon the black glossy back, and far out upon the midnight waves, which gently
chafed the whale's broad flank, like soft surf upon a beach.
Ahab and all his boats crew seemed asleep, but the Parsy, who crouching in
the bow, sat watching the sharks that spectally played round the whale and
tapped the lights planks with their tails. A sound like the moaning in
squadrons over asphaltites of unforgiven ghosts of Gomorrah, ran shuddtering through the air.
Startled from his slumbers, Ahab face to face, saw the Parsy, and hooped round by
the gloom of the night, they seemed the last men in a flooded world. "I have
dreamed it again," said he of the heares.
"Have I not said, old man, that neither hearse nor coffin can be thine?"
And who are hurst that die on the sea?
But I said, old man, that dare thou couldst die on this voyage, two hurses
must verilely be seen by thee on the sea. The first not made by mortal hands,
and the visible wood of the last one must be grown in America.
I I a strange sight that, Parsy, a hearse and its plumes floating over the
ocean with the waves for the pawbearers.
Huh? Such a sight we shall not soon see.
Believe it or not, thou canst not die till it be seen, old man.
And what was that saying about thyself?
Though it come to the last, I shall still go before thee, thy pilot.
And when thou art so gone before, if that ever befall, then air I can follow,
thou must still appear to me to pilot me still. Was it not so?
Well, then did I believe all you say, oh my pilot? I have here two pledges that I
shall yet slay Moby Dick and survive it.
Take another pledge, old man, said the parsy as his eyes lighted up like
fireflies in the gloom. Hemp only can kill thee. The gallows, you mean. I am
immortal then, on land and on sea, cried Ahab with a laugh of derision. Immortal
on land and on sea.
Both were silent again as one man. The gray dawn came on and the slumbering
crew arose from the boat's bottom and air noon the dead whale was brought to the ship.